All right let's now deal with when someone
자, 이번에는 상대가
reaches to the far side of your body
제 몸의 반대편으로 손을 뻗는 경우를
whether it's to your far side leg or
다리 쪽이든
far side of your head and as
머리 쪽이든 말이죠.
you see as we talked about earlier so
앞서 이야기했듯이,
when the arm's here I can attach
팔이 여기 있으면 제가 붙잡을 수 있는데,
it when he takes it to
상대가 팔을
the far side so either to
반대편으로 가져가면, 즉
my head here okay or looking
제 머리 쪽이나,
for like grips here or going to
어떤 그립을 찾으려고 하거나,
these these grips like this trying
이런 식으로 잡으려고 할 때
to scoop it with my left arm
제가 계속 해왔던 것처럼 왼팔로
like I've
퍼올리려고 하면
been doing it's going
상당히 바빠질 겁니다.
to be really busy.
그리고 잘 통하지도 않을 거고요.
And it's just not going to work.
좋습니다.
Okay.
여전히 잡을 수는 있습니다. 결국
So I can still get it I will
왼팔로 퍼올리게 될 텐데,
end up scooping with my left arm.
다만 방식이 조금 달라야 합니다.
But I just have to do it.
네.
A slightly different way.
먼저 정강이에 손을 짚은
Okay.
상황부터 보겠습니다.
So we'll go from the hands on the
토레안도 패스를 하거나 노스-사우스로
shins first so that's pretty common
이동할 때 흔히 나오는
way people will toriando as they
장면이죠.
or work towards north-south.
좋습니다.
Okay.
여기서 무릎을 단단히 모아줍니다.
So what I do here keep my knees tight.
아, 죄송합니다.
Actually sorry.
나중에 '리버스 최바'를 다룰 건데,
And I should say we're going
그건 이 상황을 조금
to go through the reverse joy
다르게 대처하는 기술입니다.
bar which deals with this
하지만 지금은
in a slightly different way.
다시 '일반적인 최바' 형태로
But for now we're just
연결하는 방법을
going to try and pass
시도해 보겠습니다.
it back to the regular joy bar okay.
자, 여기서 상대가 돌아갈 때 가능하다면
So from here if I can as he goes around
몸을 접어 삼두근과
I'm going to fold up grab the tricep
손목을 잡고, 상대 팔을 제 머리 위로 넘기면서
grab the wrist pass the arm above my head
제 머리는 반대쪽으로 빠져나옵니다.
and take my head out the other side.
보시죠.
Okay.
동작을 수행하면서
And you'll see as I do that
상대 팔을 제 팔꿈치 안쪽으로
I'm starting to fold
접어 넣기 시작합니다.
it into my into my
가능하다면 말이죠.
elbow if possible right ideally
이상적인 건 여기인데, 그냥 머리 옆에
here it's possible you end up
걸쳐지는 경우도 생길 수 있습니다.
like even just next to your
아까 말씀드렸듯이 그건
head which is not as good
그렇게 좋은 상황은 아닙니다.
as I talked about before.
하지만 이상적으로는 상대 팔꿈치를 구부려서
But ideally we get it folded around
제 팔꿈치에 감아 넣고
that you know we're bending their elbow
어깨 압박까지 주는 것이
and folding it around our own elbow
좋습니다.
getting some of that shoulder pressure.
자, 일단 여기까지 오면
Right okay once we're there we're in
우리가 아는 피니시 포지션이 됩니다.
our regular finishing position.
네.
Okay.
다시 보죠. 제이든이
So again Jayden goes
노스-사우스로 이동합니다.
from north-south start.
일반적으로 움직이다가 손을 바꿉니다.
So he's going normal he changes his hand.
그때 제가 팔꿈치와 손목을 잡습니다.
Right I go elbow wrist.
제 머리를 반대쪽으로
I take my head to the
빼냅니다. 그립을 잡으면서
other side so you have to like
머리를 아래로 숙여서 통과시켜야 합니다.
duck your head under as you grab
이렇게 말이죠.
your grip so we're here.
여기서 피니시를
And we can look for the finish
노릴 수 있습니다. 만약 상대가
if he changes to the far side of
제 머리 반대쪽을 잡는 경우도
my head it's similar so he grabs
비슷합니다.
the far side of my head.
아마 공간이 조금 더
It's just probably a little
답답하게 막혀 있겠지만요.
bit more jammed up.
그래도
Okay.
손목을 잡습니다. 잡을 때
But I grab the wrist I grab it I
무릎으로 프레임을 만들 준비를 해야 합니다.
want to have my knees ready to frame.
상대가 거리를 좁혀서 패스하려 해도
So if he tries to close the
어렵게 만들어야 하니까요.
gap in to pass that's difficult okay
그 상태에서 제 머리를
as I take my head to
반대쪽으로 빼냅니다.
the other side right this one.
이 경우에는 아마 머리에 걸려서
I'll probably just get it stuck on
잘 안 빠질 수도 있지만 괜찮습니다.
the head but that's okay.
어느 정도 프레임과 거리를
I'm trying to keep some
유지하려고 노력합니다.
some frame and some distance
보통 노스-사우스 상황에서는
usually on this one because we're in north
굳이 머리를 찍어 누를 필요 없이
south you can chop straight to the armpit
곧바로 겨드랑이 쪽을
you don't need like there's no
찍어 누르면 됩니다.
point chopping the head
필요하다면 순간적으로
here you might do the
무릎을 꿇을 수도 있겠지만요.
knee down for a moment if you need to.
하지만 곧바로 겨드랑이를
But if we've got access to chop
찍어 누를 수 있다면 그렇게 합니다.
straight to the armpit okay.
그리고 피니시를 노립니다.